A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Personal, Series Z FA335
Rockefeller Archive Center
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Speeches, 1891-1958, n.d.; 8; 8 Document Box(es)
  - Support for United Negro College Fund Campaign, March 5, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 214)
    Institution: United Negro College Fund Occasion: United Negro College Fund Campaign Place: Rainbow Room, New York City Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - United Negro College Fund Campaign, May 10, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 215)
    Institution: United Negro College Fund Occasion: 2nd annual campaign broadcast Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - Edwin Carlyle Lobenstine, May 31, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 216)
    Institution: Rockefeller Foundation Place: Waldorf Astoria Hotel, New York City Subject: Tribute Format: Typed
  - National War Fund, July 13, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 217)
  - National War Fund, August 29, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 218)
  - The Will to Win the Peace, September 11, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 219)
    Institution: Detroit's War Chest and the National War Fund Occasion: Opening of Detroit's National War Fund Campaign Place: Detroit, Michigan Subject: Fund Format: Typed/Printed
  - National War Fund, September 18, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 220)
  - The Last Campaign of the National War Fund, October 1, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 221)
  - Tribute to USO Shows, December 11, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 222)
  - USO ... to News Media, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 223)
  - The Price of Peace, Summer 1946 (Box 75, Folder 224)
  - Tribute to Harry Emerson Fosdick, May 22, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 225)
  - Dr. Simon Flexner Memorial Service, June 12, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 226)
  - Williamsburg Restoration Project, June 13, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 227)
    Institution: General Assembly of Virginia Occasion: Radio platter Place: Williamsburg, Virginia Subject: Restoration Format: Typed
  - Cooperation, June 18, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 228)
    Institution: United Negro College Fund Occasion: United Negro College Fund luncheon Subject: Fund Format: Handwritten
  - USO Campaign, June 20, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 229)
    Institution: United Service Organizations (USO) Occasion: USO dinner Place: Rockefeller Center, New York City Subject: Fund Format: Handwritten
  - World War II Veterans of Pocantico Hills, September 21, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 230)
    Occasion: Address of welcome to the Pocantico Hills Veterans Place: Pocantico Hills Schoolhouse Subject: Tribute Format: Typed
  - USO Campaign, October 10, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 231)
    Institution: United Service Organizations (USO)/Community Chest Occasion: Opening of Cleveland Community Campaign Place: Cleveland, Ohio Subject: Fund Format: Typed/Printed
  - Sleepy Hollow Restoration Project, October 4, 1947 (Box 75, Folder 232)
    Institution: Sleepy Hollow Restoration Project Occasion: Preview of Sunnyside Place: Washington Irving home Subject: Restoration Format: Typed
  - Peace / Freedom, October 4, 1947 (Box 75, Folder 233)
    Institution: United Service Organizations (USO) Occasion: USO executive luncheon Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - United Negro College Fund, January 23, 1948 (Box 75, Folder 234)
    Institution: United Negro College Fund Occasion: Radio platter Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - United Negro College Fund, May 3, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 235)
    Institution: United Negro College Fund Occasion: Dinner for United Negro College Fund Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - Reminiscences, April 6, 1950 (Box 75, Folder 236)
    Institution: Chamber of Commerce of New York Occasion: Acceptance to election of New York Chamber of Commerce Place: New York City Subject: Stewardship Format: Typed
  - Brotherhood, May 16, 1946 (Box 75, Folder 237)
    Institution: International House Occasion: International House meeting Subject: Brotherhood Format: Typed
  - Cooperation, June 15, 1950 (Box 75, Folder 238)
    Institution: Pocantico Hills Occasion: Party with Pocantico Hills office staff Place: Pocantico Hills, New York Subject: Stewardship Format: Handwritten
  - Harry E. Fosdick, August 14, 1950 (Box 75, Folder 239)
    Institution: Mount Desert Larger Parish Occasion: 25th Annual meeting of Mt. Desert Larger Parish Place: Jordan Pond House, Seal Harbor, Maine Subject: Tribute Format: Typed
  - History of Village Green, August 16, 1950 (Box 75, Folder 240)
    Institution: Village Improvement Society Occasion: 50th Anniversary meeting of Village Improvement Society Place: Seal Harbor, Maine Subject: Stewardship Format: Typed
  - Opportunity Through Education, June 6, 1951 (Box 75, Folder 241)
    Institution: United Negro College Fund Occasion: WNBC broadcast Place: WNBC, New York City Subject: Education Format: Typed/Printed
  - Williamsburg Restoration, November 14, 1951 (Box 75, Folder 242)
    Institution: Williamsburg Restoration Project Occasion: Council meeting Place: Williamsburg, Virginia Subject: Restoration Format: Typed
  - United Negro College Fund, March 31, 1952 (Box 75, Folder 243)
    Institution: United Negro College Fund Occasion: United Negro College Fund Campaign dinner Place: Rainbow Grill Subject: Fund Format: Typed
  - Philipse Castle Restoration Project, November 1952 (Box 75, Folder 244)
    Institution: Philipse Castle Restoration Project Subject: Restoration Format: Typed
  - Reminiscences, May 25, 1953 (Box 75, Folder 245)
    Institution: Layman's Movement for a Christian World, Inc. Occasion: Layman's Movement luncheon meeting Subject: Religion Format: Handwritten
  - United Negro College Fund Campaign, March 24, 1954 (Box 75, Folder 246)
    Institution: United Negro College Fund Occasion: TV film text Format: Typed
  - Williamsburg Restoration Project, April 26, 1955 (Box 75, Folder 247)
  - Prayer, October 25, 1955 (Box 75, Folder 248)
  - Religion (Calendar), February 20, 1958 (Box 75, Folder 249)
  - A Childlike Spirit, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 250)
  - Are Pleasures Inconsistent with the Life of a Christian?, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 251)
  - Bible Talks, Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 252)
  - Courage, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 253)
  - Genesis 4:1-15, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 254)
  - Is a Lie Ever Justifiable?, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 255)
  - Lessons Taught by Several Parables, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 256)
  - Let Your Light So Shine, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 257)
  - Miscellaneous - 3 Items, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 258)
    Format: Handwritten/Typed
  - My Election to Phi Beta Kappa, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 259)
    Subject: Personal Format: Handwritten
  - Peter's Denial, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 260)
  - Prayer, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 261)
  - Separation From God, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 262)
  - Sabbath Day, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 263)
  - The Difficulties Inherent in the Job of Being the Only Son of a Very Rich Man, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 264)
    Subject: Personal Format: Handwritten Likely presented at the Fifth Avenue Baptist Church
  - Duplicate Copies of Printed Speeches, 1915-1916 (Box 76, Folder 265)
  - Duplicate Copies of Printed Speeches, 1916 (Box 76, Folder 266)
  - Duplicate Copies of Printed Speeches, 1918 (Box 76, Folder 267)
  - Duplicate Copies of Printed Speeches, 1918-1928 (Box 76, Folder 268)
  - Duplicate Copies of Printed Speeches, 1933-1944 (Box 76, Folder 269)
  - Duplicate Copies of Printed Speeches (Oversized), 1937-1942 (Box 76, Folder 270)
  - Duplicate Copies of Printed Speeches, 1945-1956 (Box 76, Folder 271)
  - Duplicate Copies of Printed Speeches - "I Believe" Credo, n.d. (Box 76, Folder 272)
  - White Slave Traffic, June 29, 1910 (Box 77, Folder 273)
  - Labor and Capital - Partners, January 1916 (Box 77, Folder 274)
    Institution: Atlantic Monthly Magazine Subject: Labor Format: Reprint from magazine article
  - The Personal Relation in Industry, 1917 (Box 77, Folder 275)
    Institution: Cornell University Subject: Labor Format: Printed
  - Representation in Industry, December 5, 1918 (Box 77, Folder 276)
    Institution: Chamber of Commerce of the United States Place: Atlantic City, New Jersey Subject: Labor Format: Pamphlets
  - Peace and Good Will in Industry, December 19, 1926 (Box 77, Folder 277)
    Institution: The McClure Newspaper Syndicate Place: New York City Subject: Labor Format: Reprint from Herald Tribune
  - That Brotherhood May Prevail, Novemer 19, 1937 (Box 77, Folder 278)
    Institution: International House Place: New York City Subject: Brotherhood Format: Pamphlets
  - Remarks of the Retiring Chairman [General Education Board], April 6, 1939 (Box 77, Folder 279)
    Institution: General Education Board Subject: Education Format: Pamphlets
  - Historical Report of Rockefeller Foundation, April 3, 1940 (Box 77, Folder 280)
  - Letter to the President of American Petroleum Institute, February 20, 1941 (Box 77, Folder 281)
    Institution: American Petroleum Institute Subject: Labor Format: Pamphlets
  - To Men of Vision and High Purpose, May 3, 1941 (Box 77, Folder 282)
    Institution: Fisk University Place: Nashville, Tennessee Subject: Stewardship Format: Printed
  - Why I Believe in the USO, 1942 (Box 77, Folder 283)
    Institution: United Service Organizations (USO) Ward Fund Campaign Occasion: USO Field Supervisors Staff Meeting Place: New York City Subject: Fund Format: Pamphlets
  - The Power to See It Through, September 22, 1944 (Box 77, Folder 284)
    Institution: Minnesota War Service Fund/Community-War Funds Place: Minneapolis, Minnesota Subject: Fund Format: Printed
  - The Will to Win the Peace, September 11, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 285)
    Institution: Community War Chest Corporation Gifts Committee Place: Detroit, Michigan Format: Pamphlets
  - The Last Campaign of the New York National War Fund, October 1, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 286)
    Institution: National War Fund Place: Waldorf Astoria Hotel, New York City Subject: Fund Format: Pamphlets
  - God Is Man's Crying Need (Box 77, Folder 287)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s address at the annual meeting of the Men's Class of the Riverside Church. Reprinted in Christian Laymen, No. 15, April-May 1944.
  - Addresses by John D. Rockefeller, Jr., October 2 and 8, 1915 (Box 78, Folder 288)
    Institution: Colorado Fuel & Iron Company and Denver Chamber of Commerce Place: Pueblo and Denver, Colorado Subject: Labor Format: Pamphlets
  - The Colorado Industrial Plan, January 1916 (Box 78, Folder 289)
    Institution: Colorado Fuel & Iron Company Place: Colorado Subject: Labor Format: Pamphlets
  - The Christian Church - What of Its Future, February 9, 1918 (Box 78, Folder 290)
    Institution: Protestant Council of New York City Place: New York City Subject: Religion Format: Pamphlets
  - Brotherhood of Men and Nations, June 13, 1918 (Box 78, Folder 291)
    Institution: Civic and Commercial Club Place: Denver, Colorado Subject: Brotherhood Format: Printed
  - Bible Study for Men, July 31, 1918 (Box 78, Folder 292)
    Institution: International Sunday School Association Place: Chicago, Illinois Subject: Religion Format: Pamphlets
  - Home-Made Stewards, November 1922 (Box 78, Folder 293)
    Institution: New Era Movement Place: New York City Subject: Stewardship Format: Pamphlets
  - The Business of Being a Father, February 22, 1927 (Box 78, Folder 294)
    Institution: Princeton University Place: Princeton, New Jersey Subject: Stewardship Format: Pamphlets
  - Character - The Foundation of Successful Business, February 12, 1928 (Box 78, Folder 295)
    Institution: Collier's Radio Hour Subject: Stewardship Format: Printed
  - I Believe, June 8, 1941 (Box 78, Folder 296)
    Subject: Personal Format: Pamphlets
  - An Address - United Negro College Fund, May 15, 1951 (Box 78, Folder 297)
    Institution: National Broadcasting Company Subject: Fund Format: Printed
  - Remarks of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. at the Laymen's Movement-Harvard Review Luncheon, October 25, 1955 (Box 78, Folder 298)
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Scrapbooks, 1895-1960; 9; 22 Bound Volumes
  Subseries 9 contains 22 volumes of scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings for the years 1895 to 1960.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
  The archival material has been reformatted. Access to the original archival material is restricted. User copies of the microfilm are available for scholarly research.
  - Volume 1, February 1895-April 1901 (Reel M25, Frame M 01)
    Aldrich, Abby, 92
    Articles, general: Character, taste in dress, 9; "A Good Boy" -- sketch of JDR, Jr. as student, 15; Illustration - JDR, Jr. at business, 25; Qualities as a young business man, 27-29; Personal sketch -- work, interests, etc., 57; Skepticism re wealthy JDR Jr.'s qualification to enter heaven, 69
    Asbury Methodist Church, 59
    Bible Class, 57, 60-67, 70-71, 79, 81, 89-92
    Building in Hell's Kitchen, JDR, Jr.'s plan to erect, 73-75
    Cooper Class Banquet, 94-95
    Dances, JDR, Jr. treasurer of group arranging for, 69
    Engagement, hints at, 92
    Euclid Avenue Baptist Church, 77
    Fifth Avenue Baptist Church, 55, 77
    Football manager, 11-13
    Funeral, mock, held by sophomores, 1
    Hell's Kitchen, JDR, Jr.'s plan to erect building in, 73-75
    Leather stock, 51-53
    "Liber Brunensis," criticism of college annual, 21-23
    Liquor, abolition of at banquet hall, 23
    Missouri Pacific stock - "speculative manipulation" by JDR, Jr. and Gould, 83
    Musicale and dance, 17-19
    Plagiarism, suspension of students for, 3-7
    Richmond visit, 96
    Steel combination - enlargement of, 93
    Student Club address, 84-87
    Tarrytown - conflict with Mr. Weber on construction of road, 43
    Trip to West Coast and Alaska, 35-41
    Trip to Europe, 58
    Wood, sawing 31
  - Volume 2, August 1901-January 1904 (Reel M 25, Frame M 02)
    Abby (daughter), birth of, 94-95
    Articles and editorials, 99-101
    Bible Class, 87-90, 93
    Colby, Everett, 98
    Dancing Classes, 2-3
    Engagement, 3-44
    Mexico, report of JDR, Jr. scattering old along streets of, 93
    Rockefeller, Abby A. (See also "Wedding" and "Engagement"), 1, 87
    Rockefeller, J. D., Sr., 91-92
    Subway, Captains of Industry Tour, 96-97
    Tarrytown fire, 91
    Tuskegee Institute, 91
    Wedding, 45-85
  - Volume 3, January 1904-September 1912 (Reel M25, Frame M 03)
    Articles, general, 3
    Abeyton Realty Company, 55
    Belle Moore Case, 73
    Bible Class, 1, 4-17, 20-28, 31-32, 34-36, 48, 94-95
    Congo, exploitation, 29-30
    Dowling, G. T., defends JDR, Jr. from attack by Bishop Williams, 50-52
    Grand Jury Duty, 33
    Gould, Helen, 4
    Night court visit, 69
    Oilfields, trip to with Standard Oil officials, 45-47, 49
    Pocantico - see "Tarrytown"
    Police banquet address, 96-99
    Police, JDR, Jr.'s agents reveal graft among, 99-100
    Retirement from business, 61-68
    Sheffield, JDR, Jr. and cousin seek lodging, 26
    Star Publishing Company - suit for libel, 38-41
    Subway, tour through, 2
    Tarrytown, 6, 53-54, 92, 101-102
    Trip to Europe, 18-19
    Trip to Pittsburgh, 8
    White Slave Grand Jury, 56-60, 69-89
    Women convicts, JDR, Jr. finances study of, 92-93
  - Volume 4, September 1912-June 1915 (Reel M 25, Frame M 04)
    Bible Class
    "Rich Young Ruler," 24 "A Dead Weight or Live Wire, Which?" 29 Life Not Creeds is Real Religion, 40 "Young Men Who Try to Win Don't Drink," 45
    Bomb Incident, 80-82, 94
    Brown University, Honorary Degree from, 84-86
    Bureau of Social Hygiene, 2-25, 28-35, 37-40, 42-45, 47, 94
    Cartoon - Western Maryland Railway, 40
    Chinese Porcelains, 35, 85, 95
    Colorado Strike, 49-74, 87-92
    "Fixing Life's Standards" - Speech at Brown, 39
    Horse-lover - Drives to Work - with picture, 38; another picture, 47
    IWW Disturbance at Tarrytown, 75-78, 83
    Knitting - JDR, Jr., 90
    "Lord What Wilt Thou Have Me Do?" 2-4
    Mount Desert - Barring of Automobiles, 37, 104
    Pocantico - Barn Burns, 37
    Police Department of New York - Raymond B. Fosdick Survey, 94
    Rockefeller Foundation, 4, 32, 90-91, 93
    Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, Death of, 96-103
    Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 36, 41
    "Teaching the Tango to JDR, Jr." 48
    Temperance, 45
    Ten West 54th Street House, 1-2
    Trip to West Indies and Panama
  - Volume 5, January 1915-June 1916 (Reel M 25, Frame M 05)
    Industrial Relations Commission Investigations
    (There is a good glossy print of JDR, Jr. and JDR, Sr. on p.45.)
  - Volume 6, September 1915-December 1915 (Reel M 25, Frame M 06)
    Colorado Trip
  - Volume 7, March 1916-August 1918 (Reel M 25, Frame M 07)
    Baptist Church - See "Christian Church, What of Its Future?"
    Bible Class, 51, 90
    Bureau of Social Hygiene, 67
    "Christian Church, What of Its future?" 57-66, 69-74, 78-79, 81, 84, 89-90, 92-97, 100
    Colorado Industrial Plan - See "Industrial Relations"
    Consolidation Coal Company, 3-6
    Fifth Avenue Baptist Church, 36, 52, 73
    Forest Hill, 64, 72-73
    Fort Tryon Park, 20, 33-34, 37, 40-42, 53, 76-77, 80
    Industrial Relations (See also "Personal Relation in Industry"), 1-9, 11-15, 18, 20-21, 23-29, 43, 47-49, 52, 66, 82-84, 92
    Interdenominationalism - See "Christian Church, What of Its Future?"
    Mumps, 79, 82
    "Personal Relation in Industry" 18, 20, 23, 25, 27-29, 31, 35, 37
    Pictures of various members of family, 17
    Pocantico, 12, 41, 68, 71, 77, 91
    Prohibition, 38
    Rockefeller Foundation, 12, 46
    Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 22-23, 25-26, 28
    Seal Harbor, 9, 45-46, 101
    Sunday, Billy, 28, 30, 35-36, 38-39, 67, 77
    Temperance - See "Prohibition"
    Ten West 54th Street, 19, 68, 71
    Trip to West Virginia, 3-6, 11
    Western Maryland Railway, 3-6, 11
    White Slave Grand Jury, 45
    World War I, 30-32, 35-36, 47, 50, 52-55, 67, 69, 73-74, 79, 82, 84-90, 92, 95-99
    YMCA, 54-55, 69, 73-74, 85, 98
    YWCA, 14
  - Volume 8, May 1918-December 1919 (Reel M 25, Frame M 08)
    Anti-Saloon League - See "Prohibition"
    Bible Class, 100
    "Brotherhood," 26-31
    "Brotherhood Among Men and Nations," 12, 31, 35-37, 44, 49-51, 54
    Colorado Trip (Second), 1-15, 26
    Fifth Avenue Baptist Church, 77
    Industrial Relations (See also "Colorado Trip" and "Brotherhood Among Men and Nations"), 24-32, 51-66, 68-69, 71-77, 80-81
    Industrial Representation Plan (See also "Colorado Trip"), 24-27
    Prohibition, 66-67, 72-73, 75, 77
    "Representation in Industry," 52-65, 68-69, 71-74, 77, 78
    Rockefeller, Abby A., 1, 2, 7, 9, 74, 100
    Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 78, 81
    Sunday, Billy, 55
    Wilson's Industrial Conference, 80-101
    World War I, 4, 6, 7, 11, 16-26, 33-48, 63, 70, 78-79
    YMCA, 74
    YWCA, 16-26
  - Volume 9, December 1919-February 1921 (Reel M 25, Frame M 09)
  - Volume 10, January 1922-June 1926 (Reel M 26, Frame M 10)
    Anti-Saloon League, See "Prohibition"
    Battle Creek - Stay at Sanitarium, 9, 11-12, 17, 20, 27
    Bible Class, 1-2, 20-21, 24-25, 28, 71-77, 92, 112, 132, 174
    Brown University, 2, 3, 6-7, 60, 65, 74, 133
    Bureau of Social Hygiene, 56
    Byrd Polar Expedition, 175, 187-189, 196
    Cairo Museum, 174-175, 177-181, 185-186, 189-191, 193-195
    Carillon (at Park Avenue Baptist Church), 10, 107, 110, 139, 158, 165, 167-168, 171
    Cathedral of St. John the Divine, 129, 131, 132, 134, 136, 142
    Cloisters, The, 160, 191
    Colorado Strike, 80, 84, 93
    Committee of 1,000, 120, 124-125
    Elk Basin, 15, 18-20, 22-24, 29-31, 55
    European Trip - 1925, 169-170
    European Trip - 1923, 67-69
    Fifth Avenue Baptist Church, 3
    Fogg Art Museum at Harvard, 101, 107
    Forest Hill, 61
    Fort Tryon Park, 55-57
    Fosdick, H. E., 142-144, 155-157, 174, 197-198
    Giving, principles of - articles, 140-141, 163
    Golf, 49, 51, 77
    Hampton and Tuskegee gift, 135-137, 141
    Hartford Seminary, 119, 131
    Income - $1,000,000 a month, etc., 51-56, 58, 119, 165, 167
    Industrial Relations, 9-31, 34-35, 40-41, 67, 70-79, 83, 89-94, 102-105, 161-162, 165, 181, 191
    Insulin, gift to promote use of, 64, 69
    Interchurch World Movement, 81, 89
    International Education Board, 33, 39
    International House - New York, 11, 120, 126-127, 130, 134, 138
    Japanese Relief, 68-69
    Jewish Charities, 196-197
    Metropolitan Museum, 118
    Mother Jones, 203
    Mount Holyoke, 24, 31
    Near East Colleges Fund, 142
    New York Public Library, 31-32, 41
    Park Avenue Baptist Church (See also "Carillon" and "H. E. Fosdick"), 2-5, 7, 20, 22, 72-73, 85, 175
    "Personal Relation in Industry, The," 76-79, 81, 83-85, 88-91
    Phi Beta Kappa, 182-183, 189, 191, 197
    Pocantico, See "Tarrytown"
    Presidential Nomination, Speculation regarding, 61
    Princeton Library on Industrial Relations, 10, 11
    Prohibition, 11, 21, 32, 35, 37, 42-44, 47-49, 70
    Real Estate Projects, 79, 81-82, 86-87, 116-118, 139, 166-168, 171, 195-196
    Rheims, 95-98, 101, 113, 118
    Richmond, Virginia, and area trip, 184-185
    Riverside Church, 175, 181
    Rockefeller Children, 8, 10, 33, 49, 51, 53, 59, 66, 117, 129, 136
    Abby's Wedding, 134-135, 144-154, 158 Abby's Arrest for Speeding, 91-94, 97-98, 101
    Rockefeller Foundation, 64
    Rockefeller, J. D., Sr., 49, 51, 84, 88, 139, 161-162, 164
    Senate Oil Investigation, 51-56, 58
    Somerset County, 11-17, 21-24, 27, 29-31, 55
    Squash, 61-62
    Straton, Rev. J. R., criticism of JDR, Jr. and also H. E. Fosdick, 112, 115, 117, 144, 159-160, 197-198
    Survey Graphic Magazine, 19
    Tainted Money, 71, 182
    Tapestries (Hunt of Unicorn), 34-38, 40, 43, 45-51
    Tarrytown, 174
    Threat to JDR, Jr. by Crank, 58-59
    University of Chicago Divinity School, 164
    University of Tokyo Library, 124-125, 127, 129, 131, 201-202
    Versailles, 106, 111, 114, 194-195
    World War I, 4
    Yellowstone Park Trip, 108-111
  - Volume 11, June 1926-January 1929 (Reel M 26, Frame M 11)
    Apartment Project in North Tarrytown, 138-154, 171
    Brown University, 37-43, 46
    "Business of Being a Father, The," 24-25
    "Character, The Foundation of Successful Business" (Speech itself and other references to honor in business. See also "Stewart Case" for more references.), 52-55, 62, 89-90
    Chartres Cathedral, 126
    Cite Universitaire, 170B
    Colgate-Rochester Divinity School, 189
    Colorado Strike 1927, 52-53, 64
    Consolidated Coal Company, 90-94, 118, 127
    Ethical Culture School, 20
    Euclid Avenue Baptist Church, 1, 21, 23-27, 31, 42
    Fisk University Commencement Address, 120-122, 124-126, 129, 134, 136, 151
    France - Gift to (See also "Chartres" and "Rheims"), 32, 35, 36, 41
    Frick, Henry C., 83
    Fontainebleau, See "Rheims"
    Fort Tryon, 13-15
    Gary, Judge, 55
    Great Smokies, 84, 87, 190
    Industrial Relations, 25-27, 31, 64, 90-94
    Interdenominationalism, 57-58
    International House, Berkeley, 47-48, 65
    International House, New York, 192
    Japanese Screen - Purchase of, 46, 66
    Jerusalem Museum, 48-51, 56, 60, 64
    Jewish Charities, 8, 11-13, 32, 56, 190
    Lafayette National Park - See "Mt. Desert"
    League of Nations Library, 42, 44-46
    Library of Congress Gift, 58
    Lindbergh Flight to Canada with Serum for Floyd Bennett, 96-100
    Lindbergh Visit to Pocantico, 155
    McCormick, Edith Rockefeller, 9
    Men's Bible Class, 15, 62
    Mount Desert, 66, 174, 177
    "New Yorker Profile," 131-134
    Noguchi, Hideyo, 135
    Northern Baptist Convention, 24, 80
    "Peace and Good Will in Industry," 14
    Phi Beta Kappa, 13
    Pocantico, 10-11, 29, 62, 80, 130, 155, 159
    Presidential Nomination, Speculation regarding, 79
    Princeton University, 11
    Prohibition, 54-56
    Real Estate Projects, 12, 17-20, 67, 81, 93-94, 138-154, 171, 173, 175, 189, 199
    Redwoods, 8
    Rheims (See also "France, Gift to"), 31, 37A, 61, 73
    Riverside Church, 15, 16, 50-51, 83, 95
    Rockefeller, Abby, 28-29